RAJESH KUMAR

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Linkedin

<u>rajesh64727@gmail.com</u>
+91 998-087-4440

Profile

11+ years dev experience. Develops web applications and related services with modern web technologies. Having prior experience in game development.Co-founded AnjuraFashions, a fashion startup.

Skills

Frontend Dev

Develops in plain JavaScript as well as using libs and frameworks

Backend Services

Develops mostly using Microsoft technologies, sometime with open-source also.

Project Management

Leads the web dev team currently. Have run a fashion startup for more than 2 years.

Technical

HTML5	C#, C++, PHP	MS SQL Server
CSS, SASS	WCF Services, WebAPI	MySQL
ReactJS, KnockoutJS, ASP.net	IIS, nodeJS, Express	SQLite
Javascript, jQuery		
Wireframe Sketcher, Adobe XD		

Experience

Knowledge Adventure India Pvt. Ltd, Bengaluru, India Dec 2010 onwards Lead Web Developer

Responsible for development and upkeep of web applications and services.

Web application development and support (as IC and Team lead).

Backend services (WCF, WebAPI) development (as IC).

Co-ordination with web-design, SEO, Game clients, QA and marketing teams.

Google Analytics report analysis and code update.

Build preparation and deployment to Azure Classic services.

Payment gateway integration across the verticals.

Membership plans and virtual coins purchase flow integration.

Localization (currently 8 languages) co-ordination and implementation.

Integration of .net and PHP (Joomla CMS) code in web applications.

Legacy to new framework code migration.

Gameshastra Solutions Pvt. Ltd, Hyderabad, India Senior Game Developer

May 2008- Nov 2010

Game development for PC, WII and PSP platforms, using C++, C#, ASP.net, DirectX and OpenGL $\,$

Online Gaming System - Web developer- (ASP.net, C#)

Rangy Lils – Porting – PC to WII

SushiPack - Prototype development- WII

SkyScrapper Twins – Prototype development - PSP

FreeShotFrenzy - Porting - iOS to Android

P K Services, Chandigarh, India

Oct 2007- May 2008

Senior Executive

ASP.net/C# developer for a web-based Milk procurement and distribution solution

Tech Support Engineer
Desktop/ Network support, Logistics and vendor correspondence.

Honda Siel Cars India, Greater-NOIDA, India
EDP Executive
MIS development, Vendor/ Dealer correspondence and Warranty cycle update.

Education

Indira Gandhi National Open University, India
Master of Computer Applications — First Division

2005 - 2007

Rajesh Kumar — rajesh64727@gmail.com — +91 998-087-4440